Guide to the Kezia Snyder Papers MSS.324
Fales Library and Special Collections
Kezia Snyder Papers
1978-2011
1990-2011
Fales Library and Special Collections
Snyder, Kezia
MSS.324
1 linear foot in 1 record carton, 2 card boxes, and 1 CD box
4 videocassettes (vhs)
2 audiocassettes
1 videodisc (dvd)
1 sound disc (cd)
Kezia Snyder is a New York City based natural foods chef and wellness consultant. This collection consists of materials Snyder collected during her career between 1978 and 2011. Materials include four VHS tapes, two audiocassettes, one CD, one DVD, newsletters, articles, clippings, pamphlets, and lists related to macrobiotics and healthy living.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Kezia Snyder in 2011; additional materials were donated in 2012. The accession numbers related to these gifts are 2011.324 and 2012.234.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Biographical Note
Kezia Snyder is a New York City based natural foods chef and wellness consultant. Snyder has cooked healthy, organic, local, sustainable and macrobiotic food and taught the principles of a balanced, healthy, globally conscious lifestyle for over thirty years. She has been involved with the macrobiotic community in New York and the East Coast since she began reading books written by George Ohsawa, the founder of the macrobiotic diet, in 1969.
Sources:
https://www.facebook.com/KeziaSnyderHealthyLiving/
http://keziasnyder.blogspot.com/
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact fales.library@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Related Materials
Shizuko Yamamoto Papers (MSS 225)
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials Snyder collected during her career as a natural foods chef and wellness consultant between 1978 and 2011 that document macrobiotics and healthy living. Materials include four VHS tapes, two audiocassettes, and one CD related to wellness exercises, cooking, organic farming, sound healing, and laughter; one DVD related to the production of metals using non-metallic graphite; and various monthly newsletters that document the macrobiotic and wellness community in New York City. The collection also includes articles and clippings related to recipes, health and wellness, and nutrition; lists of foods found in organic and macrobiotic diets; and pamphlets related to conferences and workshops, vegan and vegetarian restaurants, descriptions of various types of grains and vegetables, nutritional services, and the ecological impact on nutrition.
Separated Materials
Two boxes of books were removed at the time of accessioning and added to the Fales Library collection.
Macrobiotic diet.; Food Consultants.; Local foods; Health food cooking; Nutrition
- Newsletters, conferences, workshops, 2000-2011 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Newsletters, clippings, articles, pamphlets, 1986-2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Earth Save, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Newsletters, clippings, articles, 1981-2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Newsletters, clippings, articles, lists, 1978-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Newsletters, pamphlets, 1999-2010 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Newsletters, clippings, articles, pamphlets, 1994-2010 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
- Newsletters, articles, pamphlets, 1979-2010 (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
- Newsletters, articles, pamphlets, lists, 2001-2008 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Newsletters, articles, pamphlets, 1998-2011 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
- VHS - Bounty from the Sea, 1996 (Box Shared Fales 014)
- VHS - Cooking for Women's Health, 1996 (Box Shared Fales 014)
- VHS - Energize Yourself with Self-Massage, 1992 (Box Shared Fales 014)
- VHS - Barefoot Shiatsu, 1990 (Box Shared Fales 014)
- CD - Organic Farming Song & Chetana, 2001 (Box Shared Fales 007)
- DVD - Quantum Rabbit Production of Metalas From Non-Metalic Graphite, 2008 (Box Shared Fales 007)
- Audiocassette - Healing Mealtime Music, undated (Box Shared Fales 013)
- Audiocassette - Laugh: For the Health of It!, 2002 (Box Shared Fales 013)